LUKE VELLA

Front-End Developer

+356 79 494 793

me@lukevella.com lukevella.com

SUMMARY

I am a front-end developer with over 5 years of professional experience. Most of my work has revolved around creating large scale single-page applications and responsive user-interfaces. I enjoy staying on the bleeding edge of technologies and discovering better and more efficient ways to improve my workflow. My strong design background allows me to both communicate my thoughts effectively when working in a team but also work independently.

EXPERIENCE

ARTWALK artwalknyc.com

iOS Developer

Jul 2014 - Present

- · Created a content management system built-on Wordpress for the iOS app.
- · Created the ArtWalk iOS app.

Technologies Used: Swift, AFNetworking, Xcode, Wordpress.

ZEEPEX zeepex.com

Front-End Developer & Designer

Jul 2012 - Present

- Created a web application that lets users search for job candidates on the web and the Zeepex database based on factors such as skills, work history and location.
- Created a javascript plugin that can find all social profiles belonging to a person by crawling links and comparing details of the parsed profiles.

Technologies Used: BackboneJS, MarionetteJS, RequireJS, Yii Framework.

AWH POKER

Web Developer

Feb 2009 - Nov 2011

- Created a web application that leveraged the gaming network's API to display information from the network's back-office to the poker room's users.
- Created the companies landing pages and affiliate marketing tools.

Technologies Used: Codelgniter, Wordpress

SIDE PROJECTS

FREESHOT - DRIBBBLE CLIENT freeshotapp.com

Creator, Designer & Developer

Freeshot is an iOS app for the Dribbble design community. It has received over 20,000 downloads on the App Store.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MALTA

B.Sc. (Hons.) ICT Computer Science & Artificial Intelligence

Oct 2009 - May 2012

CKI	1.1	C

HTML/CSS	Javascript
HTML5, CSS3, SASS,	BackboneJS
Compass, Bourbon	RequireJS, I

BackboneJS, AngularJS, RequireJS, NodeJS, jQuery **Design** Photoshop, Sketch, Illustrator, UI, UX

Other Languages Swift, Objective-C, PHP. Java **Databases** MySql, MongoDB Misc.

Unix, Git, Apache Gulp, Bower, Xcode